Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/ gregoryalanwaters (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Program Management Project Management Integration

Certifications

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt ICAgile Certified Professional in Agile Team Facilitation (ICP-ATF)

Honors-Awards

Verizon DevOps Spotlight Award
Ovation Award

Director's List

Verizon IT Outsourcing Spotlight Award

Verizon Leadership Spotlight Award

Greg Waters

Senior Manager-Enterprise Cyber Services at Verizon Dallas-Fort Worth Metroplex

Summary

I'm a Senior Manager of Program & Project Management for Enterprise Cyber Services at Verizon. My team and I execute a security services-driven strategy and operations model within Verizon Cybersecurity. We keep the focus of our people, processes and technologies on executing the fundamentals, delivering strategic and measurable outcomes and commitments, and running cyber operations like a business.

Since joining Verizon in 2001, I've been recognized for leadership and innovative approaches in program and project management, process improvement, business case planning and execution, field engagements and user experience, program and product marketing, communications, storytelling and presentations for Verizon senior leadership and C-level executives.

A certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt, I earned a Bachelor of Science degree in Business Administration from the University of Arkansas (Go Hogs). While at Verizon I also earned a Master of Information Technology degree, as well as a Master of Science degree in Project Management (MSPM) from The George Washington University which named me to their Directors List for outstanding scholastic performance. I'm also a certified Project Management Professional (PMP).

Experience

Verizon

21 years 7 months

Senior Manager-Enterprise Cyber Services at Verizon November 2016 - Present (6 years 6 months)

Dallas/Fort Worth Area

Certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt and Senior Manager-Program & Project Management for Verizon Corporate Information Security (CIS). Focus on

providing program & project management, budget & headcount management, business operations & support, as well as common services for CIS Enterprise Cyber Services (ECS) organization.

Initiatives & results include:

- > Leading (Top Performer) Rating: Achieved leading rating from executive leadership for program, project and leadership contributions to the organization for work completed in 2020. | Leading = Employee sustained performance above goals, requirements and expectations.
- > National Institute of Standards & Technology (NIST) Cybersecurity
 Framework (CSF) Reassessment: 38 Identity & Access Management (IAM)
 cybersecurity projects chartered & implemented | 5 weekly workgroups
 facilitated | 350+ Jira milestones | 200+ artifacts cataloged | NIST CSF maturity
 increased by over 50 basis points.
- > Cybersecurity Services Front Door: Standardized & operationalized cybersecurity services management front door model including 10 Confluence spaces, 10 Jira projects, playbooks & standard operating procedures.

Certified Lean Six Sigma Black Belt January 2014 - Present (9 years 4 months) Certified Verizon Lean Six Sigma (VLSS) Black Belt.

Initiatives & results include:

- > Network DevOps Transformation Model: 12 pilot enterprise systems onboarded for initial CI/CD transformational automation | 180% SVP CIO performance agreement objective achieved | \$3.8M benefits.
- > Network DevOps Transformation Onboarding: 30 enterprise systems & 70% of IT spend | 150% SVP CIO performance agreement objective achieved | target completed 4 months ahead of schedule | 30% production defect reduction | \$9.5M benefits.
- > Network Post-Change Review Testing Impact: 30% outage reduction | \$300K benefits.

- > Network BRD to Package & Close Improvement: Business Requirements Document (BRD) process 20% cycle time reduction | \$4.4M benefits.
- > OneClick Login Management Tool Deployment: 27K user rollout across VZ footprint | 90% program objectives achieved 6 months ahead of schedule | completed within budget | recognized as best practice business case | \$24.9M benefits.

Senior Consultant & Business Development Lead August 2011 - December 2013 (2 years 5 months)

Senior consultant and business development lead for Verizon. Responsibilities included Lean Six Sigma, program management, business operations, field engagement and product marketing.

As a member of the Verizon Network & Technology IT team (N&T-IT), initiatives included partnering with business and cross-functional IT teams to plan, execute and support key programs for improving the customer experience, simplifying products and processes, and increasing profitability. Focus included collaborating to establish program strategies and roadmaps, business case planning, capital and expense management, program tracking, communications and product marketing, producing internal IT articles, and providing key analysis and presentations including Key Performance Indicators (KPI), price times quantity (PxQ) and performance reporting.

Senior Consultant – Program Manager/Business Operations October 2001 - August 2011 (9 years 11 months)

Senior consultant and program manager for Verizon's VSO IT Technology Implementation & Security Architecture team.

Responsibilities included managing \$12M+ program operating budget for staff of ~100 onshore and offshore resources. Created and managed annual CIO business cases which optimized program resources and ROI, and aligned with strategic organizational objectives and performance agreements. Full life cycle project management practices including triple constraint, Work Breakdown Structure (WBS), Resource Breakdown Structure (RBS), scheduling, estimating, budgeting, capital and expense management, resource allocation and usage analysis, billing, hardware/software procurement, Statements of Work (SOW) and vendor management, program monitoring and tracking, risk management, Earned Value Analysis (EVA), metrics gathering, status and financial reporting to executive management, Program Management Office (PMO) compliance and project closeouts.

Initiatives included business operations of a single sign-on (SSO) enterprise identity management and centralized access control program; Ongoing IT Security maintenance and support budget management covering information security, compliance, global clearance, audit, policy integration, identity management and federation services; IT compliance services program management covering application on-boarding, data enrichment, access certifications and provisioning automation; Business Continuity Planning (BCP) and emergency work stoppage support.

Nortel Networks
Senior Consultant & Project Manager
July 2000 - September 2001 (1 year 3 months)

Served as implementation manager for My Nortel Networks - a consolidation of several global eBusiness applications into one personalized portal for registered internal and external users. Developed project plans and executed migration of Customer Account Pages (CAP) application, including all user data and files across several platforms. Migration included identification and execution of deliverables, risk assessment, formal documentation, resource management, data migration, functional testing, implementation and customer training.

Following implementation of MyNN, directed all post-production software builds as Level 3 application support manager. Worked with Business team owners and account administrators to manage support requests and work orders, created, tracked and closed cases in Remedy, provided technical as well as functional product information and training, assigned and tested bug fixes and enhancements, supervised entire weekly build cycles, and provided senior management and administrators release notes on a regular basis.

Additionally, served as a lead application manager for Nortel Service Network migration, designed to significantly reduce the complexity of corporate eBusiness architecture, improve overall reliability, simplify administration and troubleshooting, and significantly improve application performance. Directed CAP migration to the Service Network, scoped requirements, set and managed deliverables, and coordinated efforts with senior management of other Nortel eBusiness applications.

iChoose Project Manager January 2000 - July 2000 (7 months)

Coordinated multiple eBusiness programs and software releases for an Internet shopping bot startup, which directly contributed to a 4,000% growth in users over a six-month period. Served as lead project manager for business development and consumer marketing projects. Performed iterative software and web development with teams from Business Development, Consumer Marketing, Engineering, Creative, QA and Consumer Support. Developed and implemented software integration bundles for various distribution partnerships. Composed specifications and use cases for various consumer and business marketing initiatives. Established firm deliverable dates and assigned appropriate resources to insure each component was completed on or ahead of schedule. Conducted extensive clean machine product testing in close conjunction with QA. Executed data queries and directed DBA reporting efforts for various consumer and partner analysis. Assisted and resolved consumer support issues. Also performed light coding on sections of the corporate Internet and Extranet.

Maersk Line
Project Manager
June 1999 - January 2000 (8 months)

Managed the business and technical process designs of a \$90M shipment management software project of a Fortune 200 subsidiary (formerly Sea-Land Service, Inc., acquired by Maersk). Defined and set scope requirements for enhanced software functionality as well as bug fixes. Performed process and construction analysis, integration testing, and implementation reporting and activities. Developed use case scenarios for testing and training. Worked with senior project managers and development team to manage the project scope and meet budget and schedule objectives. Identified and deployed appropriate resources to support the development efforts. Assigned project responsibilities to team and motivated staff to achieve project objectives. Wrote and published release notes for quarterly and maintenance releases of the software application. Tracked end-user expectations and refined work plans to satisfy requirements, and provided overall customer support.

Southwest Securities 4 years 2 months

Project Manager & Web Developer June 1998 - June 1999 (1 year 1 month)

Conceived, designed, developed and managed a financial e-commerce Internet portal for a financial services holding company. Full product lifecycle experience, including directing a DBA, graphic artists and staff of developers, coding, project planning, site content and layout, functional and compliance QA, FTP, research, marketing, billing, customer support, affiliate programs, and reporting to senior management of the holding company. Experience also included development and coding of financial applications for Mydiscountbroker.com (a Top 10 online brokerage at the time). Also performed additional design and development work for the following Web sites: Westwood Holdings Group (a mutual fund company), LOGIC (a local government investment company), InternetDFW.com (a Dallas/Fort Worth information portal), and Southwest Securities Group, Inc. (an investment banking and financial services firm).

Assistant Vice President
May 1995 - June 1998 (3 years 2 months)

Conceived, designed, coded, implemented and managed a fixed income Intranet site for a mid-sized diversified financial services holding company. The site included online bond offerings in real-time using HTML, Cold Fusion, SQL and Java. Also designed and coded a temporary site for the Municipal Underwriting division of the firm. The site provided investors and salesmen the latest information on a large underwriting, \$169M Texas Public Finance Authority, for which Southwest Securities was senior manager.

Education

The George Washington University

Master of Science in Project Management (MSPM)

University of Arkansas at Fayetteville
Bachelor of Science in Business Administration (BSBA), Finance